PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(metal clattering)
- Now that you are comfortable
现在我们对弹簧的作用方式
with how springs expand and contract,
有了一定的了解
we can try something a little bit different.
我们可以做一些不一样的东西了
Let's try connecting a bunch of springs together like this.
现在我们试着把一束弹簧像这样连接起来
When we simulate springs,
当我们模拟弹簧的时候
we don't draw them using the zigzag pattern.
我们不是用锯齿模式的
Instead we use lines,
而是用
which can expand and contract.
可以伸缩的线
This gives us a really bouncy strand of hair,
这能给我们很有弹性的头发
but it's a bit too bouncy.
但是这也看上去太弹性了
Notice the hairs take a really long time to settle down.
我们发现头发要过很久才稳定下来
This isn't very realistic.
这就不真实
Take a look at our reference shots again.
看下我们的参考视频
See how quickly the hairs come to rest,
我们看到头发稳定的很快
just a few bounces.
只是弹了几下
You might think changing the spring stiffness will fix this,
你可能觉得修改弹性系数能解决这个问题
but look what happens.
但看看结果呢
Both low and high stiffness values
无论设高还是设低
still result in hair which never settles down.
结构都是这样
Our solution to this is adding
我们的解决方法其实是
what's called a damper to each spring.
给每个弹簧添加一个减震器
A damper is something that resists
减震器能保证弹簧
fast changes in displacement,
快速的变形
and it's used to bring springs
但又能使弹簧
to rest much more quickly.
更快速地稳定下来
Check this out.
看看这个
Here we have the same strand of hair as before,
这是之前的
except each spring is connected to a damper,
每个弹簧都连接到一个减震器
and we can change the amount of dampening
我们还可以改变阻尼系数
using this new parameter.
使用这个新的系数
If we increase damping,
如果我们增加他
the springs resist quick changes,
弹簧变化的快
and therefore come to rest much faster.
稳定的也快
However, too much damping will result
但是太大的话
in really stiff hair,
就会令头发变得很硬
which isn't natural,
那看上去就不自然
and here's what it looks like
这里就是这整把头发
with a whole bunch of hair.
看上去的样子
We went through a similar exercise
我们经历过同样的探索
in the early stages of modeling Merida's hair.
在早期为merida的头发建立数学模型的时候
We were trying to get the right mixture
我们想要有得到弹性系数和阻尼
of spring stiffnesses and damping
真实的作用效果
so that we could achieve the desired artistic look,
这样我们才能达到艺术上的真实感受
but with the wrong settings,
但是因为设置错误
the springs start fighting each other,
头发之间就开始碰撞
and you get pretty funny results.
你就得到了很搞笑的结果
So the trick is to find a nice balance
所以诀窍就在于要找到一个平衡
between spring stiffness and damping.
在弹力系数和阻尼之间的平衡
You can try this out in the next exercise.
在下一个练习中 你可以试试这个
Here you can control damping of each spring,
这里你能空持每个弹簧的阻尼
number of hairs,
头发数量
number of springs per hair,
每个头发的弹簧数量
and spring stiffness.
以及弹力系数
See if you can come up with something
看看你能不能做出什么
that behaves a bit more realistically. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
看上去更真实的东西来